Maksym Solomkin

Contact information: Kyiv, Ukraine

Phone: +380992819883 GitHub: github.com/solomkinmv E-mail: solomkinmv@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/solomkinmv

Summary:

Senior software engineer with experience in the development of distributed systems with millions of active users. Experienced in team management and delivering new services as well as maintaining and evolving them in production. Assiduity and great passion for programming make me prepared for the challenges as well as solving them efficiently according to the deadlines.

Experience:

Java Developer - Playtika

Dec 2017 - now

Accelerated feature delivering lifecycle and increased stability for one of the core product aspects by investigating the architecture of one of the oldest services and extracting main functionality to separate microservice which allowed flexibly and rapidly implement new features. As a team leader became responsible for lifecycle of 7 services from design and development of the new features to monitoring in production and handling production issues. Delivered 2 out of 5 most successful game features.

<u>Technologies</u>: Java, Spring Cloud, microservices, MySQL, Kafka, Docker.

Middle Java Developer – Luxoft

Apr 2017 – Nov 2017

Support of big project for processing financial data. Reduced integration efforts for trade processing flow by allowing to add new markets without changing configuration and redeploying.

Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, Maven.

Junior Java Developer - SoftServe

Apr 2016 – Mar 2017

Slashed 50% of time spent on smoke testing for QA Engineers by implementing test automation tool with flexible XML configuration, rich reporting and assertion mechanism for testing API of the project. <u>Technologies</u>: Java, Spring Framework, Maven, SOAP.

DevOps Engineer - SoftServe

Dec 2015 - Apr 2016

Implemented POC version of distributed system to collect, analyze and store logs and metrics which allowed to simplify the monitoring of other systems.

<u>Technologies</u>: Cloud infrastructure, Apache Mesos, Kafka, ELK-stack.

Projects:

Glossary – web-service to learn new English words. Used Flickr, Amazon Polly, Amazon S3 and Yandex Translate APIs to implement the functionality of project services. System is built using microservices architecture by means of Spring Cloud Framework. Authentication implemented using JWT and Spring Security. *Technologies*: Java, Spring Cloud, Angular 6, Kubernetes, AWS.

Professional skills:

- Distributed Systems
- Software Architecture and Design
- Algorithms
- Design Patterns
- SQL and noSQL Storages
- Machine Learning

Qualifications:

- Java (proficient)
 - Spring Framework, Spring Cloud
 - o JPA, JDBC, Hibernate
 - o Test frameworks
- Python (intermediate)
 - o Flask, Django
 - o iPython, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn
- C, C++, C#, Scala (academic experience)
- JavaScript, TypeScript (academic experience)

Additional courses (details & more courses in LinkedIn):

Coursera Java Specialization, Java, Scala, Machine Learning, etc.

Udemy Spring Framework, Java Multithreading, etc.
Oracle Java SE 8 MOOC: Lambdas and Streams

Cisco CCNA, IT Essentials

Other Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Big Data

Certifications:

Oracle Oracle Certified Associate [link], Oracle Certified Professional [link]

Education:

National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

2013 - 2018

Software Engineering. Heat Power Engineering Department

bachelor's degree diploma with honours, master's degree diploma